자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀.
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
죄송합니다만, 개인 파티입니다
Sorry, private party.
이봐요. 우리보고도 안 된다고
하기예요?
Come on, like you're going
to say no to these?
이제 탄알을 일발 장전할 시간이네
Time to lock and load.
신사 분들, 목표물을 정하시지요
Gentlemen, pick a target.
계단 참에 있는
금발에 가슴이 빵빵한 여자요
Bottom of the stairs.
Blonde. Nice rack.
다리가 저절로 향하네요
Legs to the floor.
저 여자를 쓰러뜨리게
Take her down.
무슨 일이 일어났는지도 모를 겁니다
Won't know what hit her.
벽 옆에 있는
By the wall.
검은 머리에 목이 길고
Black hair.
Long neck.
모델만큼 섹시한 여자요
Model hot.
이번이 자네들 마지막 경기네
그러니 좋은 점수를 올리게
This is your final set,
boys, so make it count.
게임을 하면서 자네들의
부정적인 면을 없애는 거지
You work the game,
you drop your negs...
그리고 죽여주는 사람이 되는 거네
and you shoot to kill.
이게, 저...
This, uh...
이게 블라우스에 붙어 있었네요
this was on your blouse.
어머, 이런
엄청 당황스럽네요
Oh, my God,
I'm so embarrassed.
우리만의 작은 비밀로 해 두죠
It'll be our little secret.
1부터 10까지 수 중에
하나만 골라봐요
Hey, pick a number
between one and ten.
좋아요. 음... 7이요
Okay, um... seven.
어떻게 한 거예요?
How did you do that?
제가 한 게 아니에요
우리가 한 거죠
It wasn't me.
It was us.
- 저... 머리가 예쁘네요
- 고마워요
- Um... love your hair.
- Thanks.
그거 붙인 머리 맞죠?
Those are extensions, right?
딴 데 가서 알아보시죠
Take it somewhere else.
저기요!
Come on!
아뇨. 접근할 수 있어요
할 수 있어요
No, I can close her, I know I can.
절대로 쫓아가지 마
옮겨가게
Never chase.
Move on.
새 목표물로
New horse.
여자의 의견이 필요해요
I need a woman's opinion.
뭔데요? / 어느 쪽이 좋아요?
진정한 사랑과 멋진 섹스 중에?
Okay. / Which is better,
true love or great sex?
둘 다 가질 수는 없나요?
Can't I have both?
물론 되죠
Oh, yeah.
피임할 건 가지고 있어요?
Do you have protection?
아, 항상요
Oh... Always.
당신, 달리게 해 주죠
I'll race you.
이것만 걸게 해 줘요
Let me just hang this up.
이런, 맙소사!
Oh, my God!
우리가 아는 게 뭔가, 프랭크?
What do we know, Frank?
파티가 안 좋게 끝났다는 거지. 음...
Party ended ugly for, uh...
'폴 샌더스' 씨한테 말이야
"Paul Sanders."
흉기는 찾았나?
Did you get a murder weapon?
응. 얼음송곳이었네
반복적으로 사용했더군
Yeah, ice pick.
Used repeatedly.
저 얼음 통에서 찾았네
Found it in that ice bucket.
현장은?
What about the place?
개인 클럽에 개인 파티...
Private club.
Private parties.
어떤지 잘 알잖나
뭐든 사라지지
You know the drill.
anything goes.
집주인은?
The homeowner?
어, 웨인 레이놀즈야
세미나 같은 걸 주최하고 있네
Uh, Wayne Reynolds.
Runs some kind of seminar.
독신 남자들한테
여자 꼬시는 법을 가르치지
Teaches single guys
how to pick up girls.
세미나를 연다고?
Runs a seminar?
그걸 서랍에서 찾았네
Found that in a drawer.
"원하는 대로 얻으라"
"록 스타처럼 영계 꼬시기"
"Score at will."
"Nail chicks like a rock star."
이런 쓰레기 같은 시장에
한자리 차지하고 있는 놈이지
He's got the corner
on this dirt-bag market.
그것 말고 다른 사업에도
꽤 많이 손대고 있더군
He's also got quite
a little business on his hands.
맞네, 프랭크
그리고 거기에
Yes, he does, Frank.
He also...
일급 살인도 더해졌지
has Murder One.
딕테이션
이근양(kylee322@nate.com)
싱크편집
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글번역
박승연(russell000@nate.com)
데이비드 카루소(호레이시오 케인 役)
CSI 레벨 3(반장), 전문분야 : 방화, 폭발
에밀리 프록터(캘리 뒤케인 役)
CSI 레벨 2, 전문분야 : 탄도학, 스페인 어
애덤 로드리게즈(에릭 델코 役)
CSI 레벨 1, 전문분야 : 지문, 수중탐사, 스페인 어
콴디 알렉산더(알렉스 우즈 役)
검시관, 전문분야 : 법의학
조나단 토고(라이언 울프 役)
CSI 레벨 1
CSI: Miami
4x12 The Score
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2006/01/09
누군가 우리 파티 보이에게
상당히 화가 났어, 알렉스
Somebody was very angry
at our party boy, Alexx.
표식을 남길 정도로 화가 났네
Angry enough to leave their mark.
가슴에다 "L"이라고 써 놨어
They wrote an "L" on his chest.
목에 난 상처는 너덜너덜하고
Neck punctures are ragged.
한곳에 집중되어 있어
Clustered.
분노의 증거야
Evidence of rage.
여러 번 경동맥을 찔렸군
Multiple hits to the carotid.
과다 출혈이 됐지. 빠르게 말이야
Exsanguinations. Fast.
이 애는 눈을 뜬 채로
피를 다 흘려 버린 거야
Baby boy bled out
with his eyes open.
그렇군. 이 사람을 부검실로
데려가 줘. 울프 군?
Okay. Let's get him to autopsy,
please. Mr. Wolfe?
피해자의 셔츠와 뭔가가 확실히
접촉이 있었어요
Something definitely came
in contact with the vic's shirt.
그게 뭐인 것 같나?
What do you think it was?
확실하진 않아요. 하지만
색다른 종류의 섬유와 섞였어요
I'm not sure, but it's littered
with an odd kind of fiber.
- 분석실로 가져갈게요
- 그래 주게. 잠시만
- I'll get it to the lab.
- Please do that. Hang on a second.
네, 호레이시... 네
Yeah, Horat... Yes.
접니다
Speaking.
네, 경관님
Yes, Officer.
알았어요. 지금 바로 가겠습니다
Okay. I'll be right there.
고맙네, 알렉스
Thank you, Alexx.
브라운 경관입니다
와 주셔서 감사합니다, 반장님
Officer Brown.
Thanks for coming, Lieutenant.
괜찮습니다
무슨 일이죠?
Not a problem.
What do we got?
제가 전화로도 말씀드렸지만
길에서 마약을 매입하는
Well, like I said on the phone,
I picked up a girl
아가씨를 잡았거든요
scoring dope on the boardwalk.
신분증을 요구했더니
반장님을 부르라더군요
I ask her for her ID,
and she said call you.
그분을 볼 수 있을까요?
Let me see her, please.
차에서 내려 주시겠습니까?
Could you step out of
the vehicle, please?
딜러는 도망쳤다고 했죠?
You said the dealer got away?
저희가 급습하자 도망치더군요
그자가 버리고 간 건 찾을 수 없었어요
We swooped, he ran, and
we couldn't find what he tossed.
여자 분은 조사하셨고요?
You search the girl?
네. 여자 경관이 녹색 풀이 든
봉지를 다섯 개 찾았습니다
Yeah. Female officer found five
baggies of green plant material,
- 마리화나인 것 같습니다
- 다섯 봉지라고요
- could be marijuana.
- Five baggies.
뭔지 알아보는 테스트를 하고
무게를 달아야 합니다
We need to run a
presumptive test and weigh it.
네, 그러셔야죠. 알겠습니다
Yes, you do. Okay.
담아서 태그를 붙이고
제 실험실로 갖다주세요
Bag it, tag it, and get
it to my lab, please.
그렇게 하겠습니다
여자 분은 어떻게 할까요?
Yes, sir.
What about the girl?
- 제가 이송하지요. 감사합니다
- 알겠습니다, 반장님
- I'll transport her, thank you.
- You got it, Lieutenant.
마리솔
Marisol.
케인 반장님, 정말 죄송해요
Lieutenant Caine, I am so sorry.
전 그냥... 에릭한테 연락하고 싶지 않았어요
I just...I didn't want to call Eric.
무슨 일이 있던 겁니까?
What happened?
저 혼자서 약을 사려고 했어요
그리고 경찰이 모든 걸 봐 버렸고요
I made a buy for myself,
and the police saw the whole thing.
저 체포된 건가요?
Am I under arrest?
그래요
You are.
저와 같이 가시겠습니까?
You want to come with me?
가시죠
Come on.
전 절대로 폴 샌더스를 해치지 않았어요
제 친구였다고요
I'd never hurt Paul Sanders.
The guy was my friend.
세미나 연수를 같이 받았는걸요
We trained in the seminar together.
이것 봐요. 여기서 나가게
좀 도와줘요
Listen, you got to
help me out here.
이해가 안 가는 게 몇 가지 있어요
Couple things I don't understand.
좋아요
Okay.
그러니까, 당신은 어젯밤
그 방에 섹스를 하려고 들어갔다는 거죠?
Now, you went up to this room
last night to have sex, right?
여자랑 같이요?
Had the girl with you?
궁극적인 결말이라고 할 수 있죠
It's the ultimate close.
꼬시기 예술가들에게
끝내기 게임 같은 거군요?
Kind of an end game
for pickup artists?
네. 가장 중요한 거죠
Yeah, the Big Kahuna.
그리고 옷장을 열었는데
폴의 몸이 거기서 나온 거예요
Then I open the closet,
and Paul's body falls out.
좋아요, 봐요. 여기가
내가 이해가 안 가는 부분이에요
Okay, see, here's
where I don't get.
당신은 지금 침대에 뛰어들려는 참인데
You're getting ready to jump in bed,
옷장을 들여다봤다는 겁니까?
and you're looking for a closet?
이 재킷은 1500달러나 한다고요
This jacket cost 1,500 bucks.
아니, 대체 누군가의 바지를
벗기려는 찰나에
Well, who the hell
worries about a jacket
누가 재킷 따위를 신경 쓰느냐는 말입니다
when you're getting ready to
get into somebody's pants?
여자는 깔끔하지 않음을 신경 쓴다
Women notice neatness.
당신네 세미나에서 배운 건가요?
You learn that in your little seminar?
네. "의상은 곧 무기다"
Yeah.
"Wardrobe is a weapon."
첫 번째 레슨 중에 있었죠
It's one of our first lessons.
그럼 경찰 세미나의
작은 비밀을 알려 드리죠
Well, let me tell you all little
secret about PD seminars.
살인 사건을 신고한 사람은
The guy that calls in a murder
보통 자신이 말하는 것보다
많이 알고 있다는 거죠
usually knows a lot more
than he's saying.
이제 당신 의상을 바로 여기에
둬야 할 거예요
Now, we're going to keep
your wardrobe right here with us.
그건 어떤가요?
How's that sound?
피해자를 얼마나 잘 알고 계셨죠?
How well did you know the victim?
폴은 제 학생들 중 하나였습니다
Paul was one of my students.
네. 그 세미나에 대해선 들었습니다
Yeah, we heard about your seminar.
정확히 뭘 가르치시는 거죠?
What exactly is it that you teach?
여자를 꼬시는 기술에 있어서
자신감 있고 도전적인 남자를 기르는 거죠
I instruct confidence-challenged
men in the art of picking up women.
그걸 바로 여기 클럽에서 하나요?
You do that here at your club?
이것 봐요. 내 수업은 이 사건과
아무런 상관이 없습니다
Look, my class had nothing
to do with this murder.
그렇군요
Okay.
그건 두고 보도록 하죠
We'll see about that.
아뇨, 이해를 못하시는군요
No, you don't understand.
전 이 일에 연루될 수 없어요
I can't be connected to this.
이제 곧 출판될 책도 있고
세미나도 전 세계로 퍼지고 있다고요
I got a book coming out.
My seminar's going worldwide.
나는 이제 막 유명 인사가
되려던 참이란 말입니다
I'm about to become
a household name.
선생님 홍보 문제에 대한 건 잘 들었지만
저희는 조사해야 할 살인 사건이 있거든요
I appreciate your PR problem, but
we have a homicide to investigate.
저기, 단지에 든 게 뭡니까?
Hey. What's in the jar?
저건 우리가 목표물 데이터베이스를
만드는 방법입니다
That's how we build
our target database.
'목표물'요?
"Target?"
세미나 때의 용어죠
It's a seminar term.
여자들이 이름이랑 전화번호를 적어서
Girls write their names, numbers,
단지 속에 넣어 두면
저희 리스트에 오르는 거죠
they put them in the jar,
they get on our list.
그리고 그 여자들이 친구들을 초대하죠
And then they invite their friends.
그러고 우리 파티에 오게 되는 겁니다
And they come to our parties.
어쩌면 그들 중 하나가 목표물이
되는 걸 용케 벗어났는지도 모르겠네요
Maybe one of them was put off
by being referred to as a target.
저걸 실험실로 가져가야겠어요
We should take it to the lab.
레이놀즈 씨, 증거 수집을 위해
옷을 가져가야겠습니다
Mr. Reynolds, we're gong to need
your clothes for exclusionary purpose.
확실히 돌려주기만 하십쇼
Just make sure I get it back...
이건 제 행운의 셔츠거든요
this is my lucky shirt.
안녕
Hey.
그래, 피해자 셔츠에서
뭐 나온 거 없어?
So, did you get anything
from our victim's shirt?
폴 샌더스 거?
Paul Sanders?
기본적인 합성 섬유에 싸구려였지 / 그래
Your basic polyester blend--
cheap and cheesy. / Yeah.
이 셔츠에서 내가 떼어 낸
이상한 섬유는 어땠어?
What about that weird fiber I gave
you that I lifted from his shirt?
그건 확실히 이상했지
이것 봐봐
They are weird.
Check this out.
그 섬유들은 실크 같았어
그렇지만 여기 단면을 봐
The fibers I pulled are like silk,
but look at this cross-section.
아, 그래... 덤벨처럼 보이는데
Oh, yeah...Looks
like a-a dumbbell.
내가 본 천연 섬유 중에
가장 절단 강도가 높은 거야
The breaking strength is the
highest I've seen in a natural fiber.
- 그럼 식물에서 나왔다는 거네?
- 맞아
- So it's from a plant?
- That's right.
그럼 뭐지, 삼? / 아니
What is it, hemp? / Nope.
넌 지금 콩을 보고 있는 거야
You're looking at soy.
폴을 공격한 사람이 누군지 간에
콩 섬유 옷감으로 된 옷을 입었을 거야
Whoever attacked him had on
clothes made of woven soy fibers.
용의자가 둘인데
그거로 좁힐 수가 있겠군
Well, I've got two suspects,
that narrows things.
- 둘 다 빨간 셔츠를 입고 있거든
- 웨인 레이놀즈가?
- They both had red shirts.
- Wayne Reynolds?
그리고 토드 매닝도
And Todd Manning.
부탁 좀 들어줘
Do me a favor, uh,
콩 섬유랑 그 두 사람 옷을
비교해 보고 연락해 줘
ran the soy fiber against their
shirts, and let me know.
고마워 / 물론이지
Thanks. / Sure.
안녕하세요 / 안녕
Hey. / Hey.
발레라 말로는 피해자의 피가
So, Valera said all victim blood
온통 얼음송곳에 있었고
조셉은 아무 지문도 못 찾았대요
on the ice pick and
Joseph found no prints.
어쩌면 난 뭔가 찾을지도 모르겠어
Well, I may have something.
그 항아리에 있던 모든 카드들의
I entered all of the information cards
필체 샘플들을 비교 측정기에 입력했어
from the club jar as writing samples
into the spec comparator.
뭐에 비교하려고요?
Running them against...?
피해자 가슴에 있던 "L" 문자랑 비교하려고
알려진 것으로 모르는 걸 얻는 거지
The "L" on the victim's chest.
Known against the unknown.
이 여자들은 다 자기들이 데이트 상대지
목표물이라는 생각은 못했을 거예요
All these women thought that
they were dates, not targets.
맞아. 저것들 중 하나는
이 "L"과 일치할 거야
Yeah, well, one of them
doubles back on her "L's."
- 너 괜찮은 거야?
- 네. 왜요?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. Why?
눈을 찌푸리고 있잖아
Because you're squinting.
전... 전 피곤해서요
I'm.. I'm tired.
못에 다쳤던 것 때문은 아니고?
It's not from the nail injury?
그게 언제적 일인데요
Oh, that's old news.
그럼 눈에 이상이 있는 건 아니지?
Okay, you're not having eye trouble?
이상은 있죠. 두 배로 일하기 때문에요
눈이 빠질 거 같아요
Yeah, I am, because I'm working
a double, and my eyes are fried.
알았어
Okay.
고리 달린 "L"이군요
So looped "L's."
헤더 라킨 같은데
Looks like Heather Larkin.
좋아요. 제가 얘기해 볼게요. 그럼 선배가
그 콩 섬유 셔츠에 대해서 알아봐 줘요
All right, I'll talk to her, and you find
out about my soy shirt, okay?
알았어. 그렇게 하자
All right, you got a plan.
네. 전 그 개인 파티에 있었어요
Yeah, I was there at the private party.
그럼 피해자인 폴 샌더스도
만났나요?
Did you meet our victim,
Paul Sanders?
사실, 그랬어요
바에서 만났죠
Matter of fact, I did.
I met him at the bar.
우린 대화를 나눴고
그 사람은 괜찮아 보였어요
We spoke.
He seemed nice.
블라우스에 뭐가 붙어 있네요
Something's on your blouse.
어머, 세상에
엄청 당황스럽네요
Oh, my God, I'm so embarrassed.
우리만의 작은 비밀로 남겨 두죠
It'll be our little secret.
그래, 그 다음엔 어떻게 됐죠?
So, what happened next?
모든 게 변했죠
그게 다예요
Everything turned,
that's what happened.
어떻게 변했다는 거죠?
Turned how?
절 갖고 게임을 하고 있더라고요
The guy started
working a game on me.
게임요?
Game?
실 보푸라기를 이용한 게임요
분명히 그게 말 거는 수단이었을 거예요
The lint game.
Apparently, that's the ice breaker.
단점 지적, 일부러 창피 주기
키스 수준의 접근...
The neg, the intentional insult.
The kiss close.
안쓰럽더군요
It was pathetic.
1부터 10까지에서
하나만 골라 보세요
Pick a number
between one and ten.
어떻게 한 거예요?
How did you do that?
제가 한 게 아니에요
우리가 한 거죠
It wasn't me. It was us.
폴이 당신을 꼬셨나요?
Did he pick you up?
그 말은, 제가 폴과
위층에 올라갔느냐는 건가요? 그랬어요
You mean, did I go
upstairs with him? Yes.
네, 그랬죠
그냥 통과시켜 준 거죠
Yes, I did.
I gave him a pass.
점점 더 좋아질 거라고 생각했거든요
I thought things would get better.
위층에 올라가서는 어떻게 됐나요?
What happened
when you got upstairs?
더 나빠지기만 했죠
It got worse.
왜 이래, 아가씨
우리 둘 다 왜 여기 있는 건지 알잖아
Come on, babe.
We both know why we're here.
내가 당신이랑 그냥 침대에
뛰어들 거라고 생각했어요?
You thought I would
just fall into bed with you?
그래
Yeah.
구역질 나는군요
You disgust me.
실패자!
Loser!
이런 망할 년!
What a bitch!
그래서 "실패자"의 의미로 "L"을
샌더스 씨의 가슴에 쓴 거군요
So, you wrote the "L" on his chest,
and it stood for "loser."
딱 실패자였던걸요
That's what the guy was.
When I ran out of there,
제가 거기서 뛰쳐나올 때만 해도
저한테 욕을 하고 있더라고요
he was still calling me names.
아주 팔팔하게 살아 있었죠
Very much alive.
아시겠지만, 문제는
그걸 증명할 수 없다는 겁니다
You know, the problem is
that we can't confirm that.
이것 봐요. 그 남자가 죽은 건 안됐지만
Look, I'm sorry the guy's dead,
별로 놀랍진 않네요
but I'm not surprised.
그건 좀 냉담한 거 아닌가요?
That's kind of callous, isn't it?
내가 냉담하다고요? 이 남자들은...
I'm callous? These guys..
이 사람들은 여자를 마치
일회용 물품처럼 여겨요
they treat women
like they're disposable.
자기네 게임의 작은 전리품 같은 거죠
Little door prizes in their game.
여자를 원하는 것도 아니라고요
They don't even want us.
그냥 자기가 여자를 가졌다는 걸
서로에게 자랑하고 싶은 거예요
They just want to be able to
show each other that they got us.
그런데 왜 그곳에 있었던 거죠?
So what were you doing there, then?
환상에서 깨어나려고요
그리고 저만 있었던 게 아니에요
Getting disillusioned,
and I'm not the only one.
그 밖에 있는 아무 여자나 할 수 있었죠
It could be any girl out there.
케인 반장님
Lieutenant Caine.
자네 연락을 받았네
I got your page.
지금 막 경찰에서 이걸 보내왔어요
특별 처리로 하라고요
This just came in from MDPD,
special processing.
이건 우선적인 일이네, 애런
This is priority one, Aaron.
다섯 봉지, 상당한 양이네요
평소 절차대로 할까요?
Five baggies, sizable amount.
Follow routine protocol?
글자 그대로
To the letter.
다섯 봉지 중 무작위로 두 개에서
Random sample, two of the bags.
반드시 무게를 재고
정확하게 분석하게. 알겠나?
You must weight and analyze
this accurately, okay?
알겠습니다. 그리고 이름은요?
Yes, sir.
And the name?
보고서에 나와 있는 그대로일세
Just as it appears in the report.
알겠습니다
Yes, sir.
연락드리죠 / 고맙네
I'll find you. / Thank you.
마리?
Mari?
에릭, 안녕
Eric. Hi.
내일까지는 같이 점심
안 먹는 거 아니었어?
I thought we weren't having
lunch until tomorrow.
그래, 맞아
We're not.
그럼, 우리 누나가 이 한낮에
여기서 뭘 하고 있는 걸까?
So, what's my sister doing
here in the middle of the day?
에릭, 난, 저...
Eric, I, um...
에릭?
Eric?
잠깐 시간 있나?
You got a minute?
무슨 일인지 누가
설명 좀 해 주세요
Somebody want to tell me
what's going on?
마리솔이 곤경에 처했네
Marisol is in trouble.
누나, 말해 봐
Marisol, talk to me.
내... 내가 부둣가 근처에서 약을 샀어
I...I made a buy near the pier.
내가 체포 도중에 개입했네
I intervened on the arrest.
그리고?
And?
케인 반장님께 거짓말을 했어
그냥 내 것만 샀다고 했는데, 실은...
I lied to Lieutenant Caine.
I said it was just for me, but I, um...
모임을 위한 것도 샀거든
I also bought for my group.
누나네 암 지원 그룹
전부를 위한 걸 샀다고?
You bought for your entire
cancer support group?
그 사람들이 얼마나
고통스러워하는데, 에릭
They're in so much pain, Eric.
대부분은 제대로 돌아다니지도 못해
Most of them can't get around.
얼마나 돼요, 반장님?
How much, H?
전부 다섯 봉지야
Five bags total.
누나, 지금 누나가 무슨 짓을
했는지 알기나 해?
Marisol, you realize
what you've done?
난 그 사람들을 위해서 산 거야
I did it for them.
누나가 누굴 위해 그랬는지는
신경 안 써
Look, I don't care
who you did it for.
누나는 지금 마약을 배포할 의도로
30g이 넘는 양을 산 거야
You buy more than an ounce
with intention to distribute,
그건 곧장 중죄가 된다고
it gets kicked up to a felony.
10년형을 살게 될지도 몰라
You could do ten years.
그... 그럼 난 이제 어떻게 해?
Well...well, what do I do?
좋아요. 이렇게 하도록 하세요
Okay, here's what I want you to do.
마리솔, 아무한테도 말하지 말아요
그리고, 에릭
Marisol, you talk to
no one, and Eric,
자넨 이 일에서 빠져 있는 거네
알아들었나?
you've got to stay away from this.
You understand?
이 일 때문에 반장님의
경력에 흠집이 나게 할 순 없어요
H, I can't let you take
the fall on this one.
알았네. 지금은 자네가 그런
걱정은 하지 않았으면 좋겠어. 마리솔?
Okay, I don't want you to worry
about that right now. Marisol?
- 어... 어디로 가는 거죠?
- 등록하러 가야 합니다
- Where... where are we going?
- We're going to booking.
조금만 더 버티고 있게, 에릭
가시죠. 이쪽입니다
You hang in there, Eric.
Come on. Right here.
콩 섬유라...
환경을 위해서도 좋고
Soy clothes...
good for the environment,
여자들도 좋아하니
모두에게 좋은 거 아니겠습니까?
women love them.
Everybody wins.
당신에게는 아니죠
Not you.
당신의 옷을 조사해 봤는데
거기에서 나온 콩 섬유가
We processed your clothes
and found soy fibers
피해자의 셔츠에서 발견됐더군요
from your shirt on the
shirt of the victim.
폴은 제 수강생입니다
특별히 이상할 것도 없는데요
Paul was my student.
There's nothing unusual about that.
우린 친구들입니다
다 같이 그냥 놀러 다니곤 하죠
We're buddies,
we're all just hanging out.
안됐지만 친구 분의
못 쓰게 된 셔츠에서
Unfortunately for you,
we found hundreds of fibers
상당한 양의 섬유를 찾았어요
on your buddy's shirt
that was murdered.
그래서 무슨 말씀을 하고 싶으신 건데요?
So, what are you saying?
섬유가 그냥 묻어간 게 아니라는 거죠
Transfer wasn't passive.
어떤 종류의 마찰에 의해
옮겨졌다고밖에 볼 수 없어요
It most likely got there
from some sort of friction.
그건 곧 두 분 사이에
언쟁이 있었다는 얘기가 되죠
It tells me the two of
you had an altercation.
우와
Wow.
똑똑한 데다 아름답다니
Smart and beautiful.
흔치 않은 조합이죠
It's a rare combination.
언쟁에 대해서나 얘기하죠
Let's talk about the altercation.
남자들의 세계에서 여자로
있다니 참 안됐군요
Too bad you're a woman in
a man's world, you know?
당신이 없는 자리에선
다들 당신을 총을 든 비서라고
I bet they call you
a secretary with a gun
칭하곤 할 게 틀림없어요
when you're not around.
사실, 전 거의 제 사격 실력만큼이나
모범적으로 일하고 있거든요
Actually, I do type
almost as well as I shoot.
그런 수작을 부리는 건 나한테 안 통해요
피해자에게 뭐가 불만이었던 거죠?
Throwing a neg doesn't work on me.
What's your beef with the victim?
폴이 처음 나한테 왔을 땐
여자는커녕 수표 한 장도
When Paul first came to me,
he couldn't pick up a check,
손에 넣을 수가 없었죠
let alone a girl.
난 폴의 본능을 일깨워 주고
프로로 만들었죠
I sharpened his instincts.
I turned Paul into a pro.
그랬는데 그 녀석이
독립하려고 하는 걸 알게 된 거예요
Then I find out he's
going out on his own,
자기만의 세미나를 시작하겠다는 거죠
starting his own seminar.
- 네가 이럴 순 없어
- 날 막을 수 없을걸
- You can't do this.
- You can't stop me.
뭐야? 이건 내가 평생을 들여 만든 거라고
Yeah? This is my life's work.
이봐. 난 내 나름대로의 방식이 있다고
그리고 그걸로 부자가 될 거야
Hey, I got my own version,
and I'm going to get rich off it.
그래? 그래
가만 안 두겠어
Yeah? Yeah.
I'll take you down.
그래요, 우린 싸웠죠. 인정합니다
하지만 폴을 죽이지는 않았어요
Yeah, we argued, I admit it,
but I didn't kill him.
이것 봐요. 내일 뉴욕에서
첫 세미나를 진행해야 해요
Look, I lead my first seminar
in New York City tomorrow.
내 홈페이지에는 하루에
1000명이나 접속하고요
My website's getting a
thousand hits a day.
아무 데도 가실 수 없습니다
레이놀즈 씨
You're not going anywhere,
Mr. Reynolds.
당신은 살인 사건의 용의자거든요
You're a suspect
in a murder investigation.
라이언, 나 캘리야
뭐 하나만 해 줄래?
Hey, Ryan, it's Calleigh.
Would you do something for me?
알렉스, 안녕하세요 / 안녕
Hey, Alexx. / Hey.
벌써 폴 샌더스를 부검하셨어요?
Did you post Paul Sanders, yet?
이제 막 시작하려는 참이야
Just about to start.
뭐가 필요한데?
What do you need, honey?
용의자에 대한 단서가 별로 없어서요
We're running cold on suspects.
폴 샌더스의 물건들을
다시 한 번 보고
I just want to take another
look through his things,
쓸 만한 게 없나 보려고요
see if I can find anything.
음, 거기 있는 봉투들에 다 있어
Hmm, they're in those bags.
벨트 주머니도 다 보셨어요?
Did you have a belt pack with him?
응
Mm-hmm.
그 안에 좀 소름 끼치는 것도 있던데
Boy had some freaky stuff in it, too.
민트 조각들에, 콘돔에...
Pack of break mints, condoms.
별로 소름 끼칠 것 같지 않은데요
Doesn't sound so freaky.
실 보푸라기를 한가득 가지고 있더라고
He had a bag of lint.
아, 맞아요. 이 사람들은
세미나에서 그런 걸 받는대요
Oh, yeah, they hand those
out at the seminars.
그건 그러니까 꼬시기 전문가들에겐
버팀목이나 마찬가지인 거예요
They're like, uh,
props for pickup artists.
저녁 식사와 영화 보기는
이제 뭔가 문제가 있는 거야?
Whatever happened to
dinner and a movie?
저도 모르겠어요
이 사람들한텐 그게 전쟁 같은가 보죠
I don't know.
It's like a war to these guys.
그건 정말 잘못된 거야
Well, that's just wrong.
이것도 그렇고
And so is this.
뭐가요? 뭔데 그래요?
What? what is it?
이 사람은 반지 자국이 있어
He has a ring indentation.
그게 무슨 의미인데요?
What's that tell you?
결혼반지의 흔적이지
Evidence of a wedding ring.
폴 샌더스가 유부남이라고요?
Paul Sanders is married?
글쎄, 이 사람 손가락은 그렇다고 하네
Well, that's what his
finger's telling me.
저도 볼게요
어디... 어디에요?
Let me see.
Where... Where is it?
띠 모양으로 피부가 움푹 들어갔잖아
바로 여기
Band of indented skin, right there.
아, 네, 맞아요. 보이네요
이거 재밌는데요
Oh, yeah, yeah, I see that.
That's interesting.
- 너 이거 안 보이는 거지?
- 잘 보여요
- You can't see it, can you?
- Yes, I can.
눈이 더 나빠졌어
거짓말하지 마, 라이언
Your eye's worse.
Don't lie to me, Ryan.
아니에요. 눈은 훨씬 좋아졌어요
No, my eye got better.
내가 처방해 준 약은
전부 먹은 거야?
You took all the pills
I prescribed you?
그럼요 / 그럼 더 이상 낫지 않을 거야
Yes. / Then it's not getting better,
염증이라면 이미 깨끗해졌을 테니까
cause an infection would've
cleared up by now.
알렉스, 걱정해 주는 건 정말 고마워요
Look, Alexx, I really
appreciate your concern.
정말이에요. 하지만 전 지금
진행중인 사건을 맡고 있다고요
I really do, but I'm working
on a case right now.
이 사람 아내를 찾아야겠어요
I got to find this guy's wife.
이제 과부가 됐다고 알려 줘야죠
Tell her she's a widow.
누군가가...
Someone...
그이를 찔렀다고요?
stabbed him?
얼음송곳으로요
With an ice pick.
저도 이게 힘든 일이라는 건
압니다, 샌더스 부인
Look, I... I know this is difficult
for you, Mrs. Sanders,
하지만 어젯밤에 남편 분과
클럽에 같이 계셨나요?
but were you at the club
with your husband last night?
뭐라고요?
What?
전 어젯밤에 집에 있었어요
I was at home last night.
실례지만.... / 괜찮아요
Do you mind if I...? / No.
어쩌다가 팔을 데이셨죠?
How did you burn your arm?
아... 이건...
Oh... I...
부엌에서 약간 사고가 있었거든요
I had an accident in the kitchen.
그래요
Oh.
이건 독특한 화상 자국인데요
That's a unique burn pattern.
티타늄과 유황이 섞인 질산칼륨에 의한 거예요
It's caused by potassium nitrate
in combination with titanium and sulfur.
그게 무슨 소린지조차 모르겠는데요
I don't even know what that means.
불꽃요
Sparklers.
클럽의 종업원들이 주문 음료를
가지고 갈 때 같이 갖고 가죠
Waitresses at the club carry
them with their drink orders.
이건... 있던 장소를 나타내는
서명 같은 거예요
It's a... sort of a
signature of the place.
그래요. 전 어젯밤에 클럽에 있었어요
하지만 당신이 생각하는 그런 게 아니에요
Okay, I was in the club last night,
but it's not like you think.
폴은 그런 클럽에 조사를 하러 가야 했어요
Paul had to go to those
clubs to do research.
폴은 비슷한 종류의 사업을 시작하려고 했죠
He was starting a similar business.
저희도 알고 있습니다
We know.
아니면 그냥 그렇게 말하는 것뿐이었나요?
Or was that just what he told you?
저는 폴을 믿고 싶었어요. 하지만...
I wanted to believe him, but...
확신할 수 없었죠. 그래서...
I wasn't sure, so...
폴을 미행했어요
I followed him.
그 여자랑 같이 있는 걸 보니
When I saw him with that girl,
폴이 그저 조사만 하는 게
아니라는 걸 알았죠
I knew that he wasn't
just doing research.
전 너무 화가 났어요
I was so angry.
폴을 얼음송곳으로 찌를 만큼 화가 났나요?
Angry enough to stab
him with an ice pick?
물론 아니죠
Of course not.
뭔가를 하기엔 너무 충격 받았거든요
I was too crushed to do anything.
폴은 저의 전부였어요
Paul was my whole world.
전 그냥 집에 와서 울었죠
I just went home and cried.
폴이 귀가하지 않았을 때
걱정되진 않으셨나요?
Weren't you worried about him
when he didn't come home?
그냥 여자랑 같이 갔나 보다고 생각했죠
I just thought he
went home with a girl.
그러면 전에도 이런 적이 있었습니까?
So he's done this before?
아뇨
No.
저흰 결혼한 지 이제 겨우 넉 달째인걸요
We've only been
married four months.
- 신혼부부세요?
- 네. 왜요?
- You're newlyweds?
- Yes. Why?
제가 뭘 좀 확인하고 올 동안에
여기서 기다리고 계세요. 알겠죠?
I'm gonna need you to wait here
while I go look into something, okay?
결혼 등록이라...
이런 건 처음 찾아보네
A wedding registry.
That's first.
누구한테 선물이라도 사 줘야 하는 거야?
Need to buy a gift for someone?
아니요. 용의자가 어떤 선물을
받았는지 봐야 해서요
No, I need to see what gifts
were bought for my suspect.
폴과 브렌다 샌더스?
Paul and Brenda Sanders?
네. 4개월 전에 결혼했다는군요
Yeah, they were married
about four months ago.
아, 너 로비에서 에릭네 누나 봤어?
Oh, did you see Delko's
sister in the lobby?
아니요
No.
내가 보기엔 또 뭔가 말썽인 거 같더라
I think she's in trouble again.
마지막이어야 할 텐데요
Last thing she needs.
백혈병이라더라
최악의 암이지
Leukemia.
Worst kind of cancer.
찾아보기나 하세요
Keep searching.
이건 아무한테도 말하지 마
아무래도 그 여자가 반장님을 좋아하나 봐
Don't tell anyone this,
but I think she's got a thing for H.
쿠퍼, 블로그 만들고 있어요?
전 지금 확실한 용의자를 잡아두고 있다고요
Cooper, are you writing a blog?
I got a suspect on ice.
알았어
Okay.
폴과 브렌다 샌더스
Paul and Brenda Sanders.
그 사람들 결혼 등록란에 들어왔어
I've tapped into their
wedding registry.
좋아요. 한참 지났네요 저건 꽤 비싼 건데요
All right, about time.
That's pricey stuff.
크리스털 펀치 그릇에, 도자기에...
Crystal punch bowl, bone china...
퐁듀 세트? 누가 퐁듀를 먹죠?
Fondue set?
Who eats fondue?
난 먹는데 / 제 말이 그 말이에요
I do. / That's my point.
잠깐, 멈춰 보세요
얼음송곳이에요
Wait, stop.
Ice pick.
800달러?
800 bucks?
누가 얼음송곳을 사는 데
800달러나 쓰는 거야?
Who pays 800 bucks for an ice pick?
중요한 건 오로지 저 물건이
구매됐다는 것과
All that matters is it's
marked "purchased" and
그게 신혼부부의 집으로
배달됐다는 거예요
was delivered to the
newlyweds' house.
이거군. 스털링 은제품
6인치에 다이아몬드 장식
There it is. Sterling silver,
six inch, diamond point.
아무래도 살인 무기 같군요
Just like our murder weapon.
샌더스 부인, 솔직하게 말씀드리죠
부인은 지금 무척 혐의가 짙군요
Mrs. Sanders, I'm gonna be blunt.
You're looking very guilty.
무슨 말씀이신지 모르겠어요
I don't know what you mean.
부인의 남편을 살해하는 데에
결혼 선물 중 하나를 사용하신 것 같더군요
Looks like you used one of your
wedding gifts to murder your husband.
그건 말도 안 돼요
That's not true.
제가 수색 영장을 받아서
If I get a search warrant,
부인의 집을 수색하면
and I search your house,
제가 얼음송곳을 찾게 될까요?
am I gonna find an ice pick?
알았어요
Okay.
사실은 우리 집에
도둑이 든 적이 있어요
Truth is, we had a
burglary in our home.
언제요? / 일주일쯤 전에요
When? / A week ago.
누군가 결혼 선물을 다 넣어 둔
차고에 침입했었어요
Somebody broke into our garage
where we stored all our wedding gifts.
왜 이 사실을 먼저
말씀하시지 않으셨죠?
Why didn't you
tell me about this before?
절 믿으실 거 같지 않아서요
I didn't think you'd believe me.
지금은 믿지 못하겠군요
경찰에 신고는 하셨나요?
Well, I don't now.
Did you call the cops?
경찰서에 가서 보고서며
온갖 거에 다 적어 넣었어요
I went down to the police station,
I filled out a report and everything.
그 보고서를 제가 봐야겠군요
I need to see that report.
에릭
Eric.
- 애런은 어디 있나?
- 법원에 나가야 한대서요
- Where's Aaron?
- He had to go to court.
전 그냥, 어...
그냥 애런의 결과를 살펴보고 있었어요
I was just looking, uh...
I was looking at his results.
알겠네
I can see that.
실험 결과 마리화나가 맞네요
Tested positive for marijuana.
압류품의 총 무게는 얼마지?
What was the total
weight of the seizure?
30g이 넘어요 / 그렇군
Over an ounce. / Yeah.
그렇게 되면 중죄지. 안 그런가?
Which makes it a felony, doesn't it?
누나는 수감될지도 몰라요
Marisol could be facing
mandatory jail time.
- 그 몸 상태로는 버티지 못할 거예요
- 나도 그렇게 생각하네
She won't make it in
her condition. / I agree.
마리솔에게 필요한 건 변호사야
그리고 나도 몇 사람 알고 있고, 에릭
What she needs is a lawyer,
and I've got some names, Eric.
누나는 아무것도 가진 게 없어요
저도 지금 빈털터리고요
She doesn't have anything,
and I'm... I'm tapped out.
그건 내가 알아서 하지
I'm gonna take care of it.
- 반장님, 이미 충분히...
- 잠깐만
- H, you're dong enough...
- Hang on a second.
지방 검사 전화야
It's the state attorney.
- 누나에 관한 걸까요?
- 내 생각도 그래
- You think it's about Marisol?
- That would be my guess.
네
Yeah.
네, 제가 맡지요
Yeah, I'll hold.
어떻게 벌써 그쪽이 알았죠?
How could they know already?
에릭, 누군가 말을 한 게 틀림없어
Eric, somebody must have talked.
반장님?
Lieutenant?
케인 반장님?
Lieutenant Caine?
저를 보자고 하셨나요?
You wanted to see me.
제 사무실에서 얘기했으면 싶은데요
I really would prefer if
we did this in my office.
그냥 여기서 얘기하면 안 될까요?
Would it be okay if we did it here?
좋아요
Fine.
지난주엔 에릭 델코가 약물 사용 혐의로
거의 기소될 뻔하더니
Last week, Eric Delko almost
went down on a dope charge.
이번 주엔 그 누나가 판매를 위한
마약 소지 혐의를 받고 있더군요
This week, his sister's facing
possession with intent to sell?
네. 그건...
Yes. Uh...
웨스트 씨, 이 건에 대해선
정상 참작할 만한 사정이 있습니다
Ms. West, there are extenuating
circumstances in this case.
어떤 거죠? / 여자 분의 경우에...
Like what? / The girl...
그분은 암이 있어요
The girl has cancer.
화학 요법에 따른 구역질을
완화시키기 위해서 산 겁니다
And she buys to alleviate
nausea from chemotherapy.
편리한 핑계네요
That's very convenient.
그래도 그게 사실입니다
Well, it happens to be the truth.
구역질을 완화시키는 데
30g이 넘는 양이 필요하진 않죠
You don't need over an
ounce to alleviate nausea.
마리솔은 팔려는 의도가 있었어요
그건 지울 수 없는 사실이에요
She was planning to sell.
This isn't going away.
알겠습니다
Okay.
이건 그냥 궁금해서 그러는데
이 일에 대해 어떻게 들으셨죠?
Just out of curiosity,
how did you hear about it?
에릭 델코는 당신의 CSI 요원 중 하나죠
Eric Delko is one of you CSIs.
그 가족한텐 분명히
잘못된 점이 있어요
There's obviously
something wrong in that family,
그리고 그것과 연관되어
반장님의 실험실 전체도 마찬가지죠
and, by association, your lab.
걱정하고 계신 건 알겠습니다만
아직 제 질문에 답하진 않으셨습니다
I hear your concern, but you're
not answering my question.
이 일에 대해 어떻게 아셨죠?
How did you hear about this?
제 정보원을 포기하진 않을 거예요
I won't give up my source.
제 실험실에 정보원이 있다는 거군요
You have a source in my lab.
이 일을 내 탓으로 돌리려고 하지 말아요
나는 당신의 문제들 중에 사소한 것일 뿐이니까요
Don't try and turn this on me.
I'm the least of your problems.
나중에 얘기하죠 / 웨스트 씨
We'll talk. / Ms. West...
우리가 왜 범행 현장에
돌아와 있는 거죠?
So tell me, why are we
back here at the crime scene?
샌더스 부부의 집에서 일어난
도난 사건에 관한
You take a look at that police report
경찰 보고서를 봤지?
on a burglary at the Sanders' house?
네, 그랬죠. 확인했어요
Yeah, I did. It checked.
그러니 그 부인은 혐의가 벗겨졌지
So the wife's in the clear.
지금으로선 그렇죠
우리 사건은 막다른 곳에 다다랐고요
For now.
And our case is stalled.
아무튼 우리 뭘 찾고 있는 거지?
Well, what are we looking for, anyway?
모르겠어요. 확실치가 않네요
I don't... I'm...I'm not sure.
방은 벌써 한 번 다 둘러봤지?
You did sweep the room
already, didn't you?
네. 그러니 아마 더 찾을 수 있는 게 없을걸요
Yeah, which means we're probably
not gonna find anything.
저건 뭐야?
What's that?
저건...
That is...
저건 펜이네요
펜이에요
That is a pen.
It's a pen.
이걸 못 봤다니 믿을 수가 없네요
Cannot believe I didn't find this.
몸통 부분이 매끄러워
지문이 찍힐 만한 표면이네요
The barrel is a smooth,
printable surface.
글씨를 쓸 때도 지금과 똑같이 두 손가락을 쓰잖아
You use the same two fingers
when you're writing...
검지와 엄지가 각각 반대쪽에 오도록 잡고
forefinger and thumb
in opposing positions.
그럼 부분 지문이 나오겠네요
So, we're looking at partials.
맞아. 거기에 충분한 지문 융기만 있으면 돼
Yeah. As long as
there's enough ridge detail.
캐런 매닝? / 잠깐만요
Karen Manning? / Wait.
왜, 저 여자 알아?
What, you know her?
벌써 얘기도 했는걸요
하지만 저런 이름이 아니었어요
We've interviewed her,
but that's not her name.
매닝이라니
Manning.
시신을 찾은 남자하고 무슨
관련이 있는 걸까?
Do you think she's related
to the guy that found the body?
우리한테 이름이 헤더 라킨이라고 하셨죠
You told us your name
was Heather Larkin.
헤더 라킨은 제 필명이에요
Heather Larkin's my pen name.
그럼 작가 분이시라는 겁니까?
So you're telling me
you're a writer?
마이애미 글로브지에 칼럼을 쓰고 있어요
I write a column for the Miami Globe.
그 클럽에도 그것 때문에 간 거고요
That's what I was doing at that club.
비밀리에 가서
I went undercover
전문적인 꼬시기 예술가들을
직접 체험해 본 거죠
to do an expose on
professional pickup artists.
아, 그렇군요
I see.
그러면, 음...
조사하러 간 거였군요
So, uh... so,
it was research.
맞아요
Exactly.
전 폴 샌더스가 절 꼬시도록 내버려 뒀어요
그렇게 해서 그 사람 기술들을 보려고요
I let Paul Sanders pick me up
so I could learn his techniques.
정말 구역질 나는군요
You disgust me.
내 칼럼이 발표되고 나면
Soon as my column's published,
다시는 어떤 여자에게도
상처 주지 못할 거예요
you'll never hurt another
woman again.
실패자!
Loser!
아야! 망할 년!
Ow! Bitch!
그러고 나서 죽은 채 발견되었죠
And then he turned up dead.
제가 그런 건 아니에요
Not by me.
그럼 또 다른 관계자는 어떻습니까?
How about another relative?
남동생인 토드가 지난밤에
그 클럽에 있었던데요
Your brother Todd
was at the club last night.
그 애를 보진 못했어요
I didn't see him.
아시겠지만, 토드가
폴 샌더스의 시신을 발견했지요
You know, he found
Paul Sanders' body.
그걸 몰랐다고 할 참입니까?
Are you trying to tell
me you didn't know that?
- 전 아는 게 없어요
- 그만 털어놓으시죠, 아가씨
- I had no idea.
- Come off it, lady.
뭐, 토드가 당신을 위해서 일하나요?
특파원 같은 거로요?
What, is he working for you?
Is he a stringer?
아니에요. 동생한테서
이 그룹에 대해 듣긴 했죠
No, I learned about this
group from my brother.
그 앤 거기에 푹 빠져 있었어요
전 동생을 그렇게 만든 게 싫었지요
He was into it.
I didn't like what it did to him.
동생을 막으려고 했었습니까?
Did you confront him?
시도는 했죠. 동생은 변호를 하더군요
그 그룹이 자기를 도와준다나요
I tried. He got defensive.
He said it was helping him,
자기 인생을 바꿔줌으로써요
that it was changing his life.
오히려 인생을 망치는 것에
가까워 보였는데요
More like ruining it.
그 사람들은 애한테 "마법사"라는
별명을 붙여 주더군요
They came up with this nickname,
"The magician",
여자한테 신비한 손길을
준다나요. 구역질이 났죠
like he had some magical touch
over women. It was disgusting.
그래서 그 사람들의 행태를 폭로해서
동생을 구하려고 했던 거군요
So by outing them in an expose,
you were trying to save your brother.
그 사람들은 여자를
훈장처럼 여기고 비인격화하죠
They exploit and
dehumanize women.
누군가는 그들을 멈춰야 해요
Somebody had to stop them.
그러면 그곳에서
동생을 보진 못한 겁니까?
And you didn't see
your brother there?
못 봤어요
No.
믿어 주세요. 만약에 봤다면
그 애한테 벌써 말했을 거예요
And believe me, if I did,
I would have told him that...
뭐라고 말하시려 했는데요?
Told him what?
제가 싫어하는 존재가
되어 버렸다고요
That he'd become
something I hate.
애런, 무슨 결과가 나왔지?
Aaron, what'd you get?
부탁하신 대로 나머지 세 봉지를
분석했습니다 / 알았네
I analyzed the other three
baggies, like you asked. / Okay.
세 봉지 모두의 무게는 30g이 넘습니다
Weight of the three baggies
puts the total over an ounce.
알았네. 거기에 무슨 의미가 있나?
Okay, and what does that mean?
반전이 있어요
There's a curveball.
처음에 제가 샘플을 얻은 두 봉지는
순수한 마리화나였죠
The first two baggies I sampled
were pure marijuana.
그런데 나머지 세 개는, 가짜였어요
The last three, bunk.
자, 잠깐, 잠깐만, 기다리게
Okay, w...wait a second,
wait a minute, wait.
가짜라. 그 '가짜'가 뭔가?
Bunk. Define "bunk."
허브예요. 네덜란드 헤이즈를
수경 재배한 싹이에요
Herb. Dutch haze,
hydroponics buds.
전부 식물 성분이고, 전부 합법적인 겁니다
All plant material, all legal.
합법적이라...
고맙네, 애런
Legal.
Thank you, Aaron.
반장님
Lieutenant.
뭔가?
What?
꼭 말씀드려야 할 것 같아서
말씀드리는 건데요
I'm gonna say this because
I feel I have to, all right?
이 실험실에 에릭 델코가 혼자
있었다는 사실이 전 마음에 걸립니다
I'm not comfortable that Eric
Delko was in this lab alone.
애런, 그건 내가 이미 확인했네
그래도 고맙네
Aaron, I've already dealt with it.
But thank you.
반장님, 누가 뭐라고 하든 상관없어요
전 절대로 증거를 훼손하지 않았어요
H, I don't care what they say.
I didn't compromise the evidence.
나도 아네, 에릭. 하지만 지금 당장
지방 검사가 올라오고 있는 중이야
I know that, Eric. But the state
attorney is on her way up right now.
반장님, 누나를 걸고 맹세코
전 아무것도 건들지 않았어요
H, I swear on my sister,
I didn't touch a thing.
자네를 믿네. 내가 해결하게 두게
저기 오는군
I believe you. Let me work on it.
Here she is.
어디 보자...
Well...
제가 말하는 쓸모 있는 정보원이란
저런 사람인데요
That's what I call an
effective source.
전 정보원 따위 없어요
사건이 있는 거죠
I don't have a source,
I have a case.
그 사건도 더 이상
존재하지 않는다고 밝혀졌는데요
Turns out, you don't
have a case, ma'am.
길에서 압류된 물건이
가짜로 판명됐거든요
The product that was seized
on the street is bunk.
가짜라고요? 그 전부가?
Fake? All of it?
- 전 20그램만 있으면 돼요
- 그거 아십니까?
- I only need 20 grams.
- Guess what?
그 20그램을 얻게 될 일은 없을 겁니다
You're not gonna have them.
이 실험에 에릭 델코가 개입됐나요?
Was Eric Delko
involved in this testing?
아닙니다
He was not.
그렇지만 샘플이 분석될 때
그 실험실에서 일하고 있었잖아요
But Eric Delko was working
in the lab when it was analyzed.
에릭은 범죄 현장 분석가입니다
He is a crime scene
investigator, ma'am.
바로 지난주에 마약에
양성 반응을 보인 사람이죠
Who, just last week,
popped positive for dope.
그건 이제 별일 아닌 일이죠
안 그렇습니까?
Now that is common
knowledge, isn't it?
심사 위원회에 이 이례적인
일을 보고하겠어요
I will be informing the accreditation
board of this anomaly.
봄에 있을 재심사는 준비가 되셨나요?
You are up for re-accreditation
in the spring?
네, 그럼요. 면밀히 감사 받을
준비가 돼 있을 겁니다
Yes, we are, and we will
be ready for the inspection.
반장님 실험실에선 정말로
증거에 부당하게 손댔어요
Your lab just tampered with evidence.
그냥 빠져나가게 두지 않겠어요
I'm not letting you get away with it.
물론 그러시겠죠
I have no doubt.
왜 저렇게까지 하는 걸까요?
Why would she do that?
소위 경력 관리라는 거네, 에릭
It's called career
management, Eric.
그렇군요. 이제 어떻게 하죠?
All right, well what do we do?
마약을 판 딜러를 찾아야지
We need to find this dealer.
- 도망쳐 버렸는데요?
- 더 이상은 아니지
- Thought he was in the wind.
- Not anymore.
누나 말로는 항상 같은 사람한테
Marisol said she scored
같은 장소에서 마약을 샀대요
always from the same guy
at the same place.
마리솔이 그 사람 수법을 말해 줬나?
She give you his M.O.?
네. 공원에 차를 세우고
돌아다니면서 살 사람을 기다린댔어요
Yeah, he'd pull up to the park,
hang out and wait for customers.
좋아. 그럼 그자의...
Okay, so we're looking...
발자취를 찾아봐야겠군
for his calling card.
음료수 캔이네요
지문이 나올지도 모르겠어요
Got a soda can.
Maybe get some prints.
두고 보면 알겠지
잠깐 있어 봐
Well, what do you know?
Hang on.
거기에선 확실히 뭔가
찾을 수 있을 것 같은데요
I think we'll be able
to get something from that.
그래. 틀림없겠군
가세
Yes, I bet we will.
Come on.
- 건진 거 있어?
- 마약을 봉하려면 이음매를 핥아야 해요
- Any luck?
- Got to lick a joint to seal it.
- 많이 해 본 사람 같네
- 전 아니에요
- You sound like an expert.
- Not me.
DNA를 CODIS에 돌려 봤어요
I put the DNA into CODIS.
키스 기포드네
"Keith Gifford."
마약 소지 및 유통, 폭행의 전과가 있어요
Priors for possession.
Distribution. Assault.
마지막으로 등록된 주소 좀 알려 줘
Give me his last known address.
보고서엔 주소가 없어요
Report doesn't list address.
고용주는 나와 있는데
그거라도 괜찮겠어요?
It's got employers.
Will that help?
응. 그럴지도 모르겠는데
Yeah, it just might.
왜 이러시는 거예요?
What the hell's this about?
네 녀석이 누나한테 마약을 팔았잖아
You sold weed to my sister.
무슨 소리를 하시는지
전혀 모르겠는데요
I don't know what you're
talking about.
전 이제 제대로 된 직업이 있다고요
마약 거래 같은 건 안 해요
I got a legitimate job.
I don't deal.
자네가 상황을 잘 이해하지
못하는 것 같군, 키스
I don't think you understand
the situation, Keith.
자넨 감옥에 가게 될 거야 / 감옥요?
You're going to jail. / Jail?
전 다시 일하러 가봐야겠어요 / 이봐
I'm going back to work. / Hey.
우린 이음매에 네 DNA가 가득한
마약 봉투가 있다고
We got a baggie full of
joints with your DNA on it.
그리고 내가 알기론, 이 주에서
마약 거래로 3번 걸리는 게 되지
And to my knowledge, you have
three priors in this state for dealing,
그게 뭘 의미하는지 알지 않나?
and you know what
that means, don't you?
타고 갈 차가 왔군
Your ride is here.
좋... 좋아요. 뭘 도와 드릴까요?
어떻게 하면 되는 거예요?
Okay... okay. What can I do?
How can I fix this?
우선, 지방 검사에게 자네 물건에
대해 솔직하게 털어놓을 수 있겠지
For starters, you can tell the state
attorney the truth about your product.
- 무슨 소리를 하시는 거예요?
- 바꿔치기 돼 있더군, 키스
- What are you talking about?
- It's been stepped on, Keith,
그 얘길 하고 있는 거야
that's what I'm talking about.
어떻게 할 건가?
What do you want to do?
제가 사실대로 말하면
형량을 줄여 줄 수 있나요?
If I tell you the truth,
will that reduce my jail time?
잘될 걸세
It'll go a long way.
데려가게
Bring him.
일이 잘 안 됐어요
Business has been bad.
약간의 수입이 더 있어야
빚을 안 지고 지낼 수 있었죠
I needed a little extra
to keep me afloat,
그래서 풀을 조금 나른 겁니다
so I move a little herb.
이 여자에게 다섯 봉지의 마리화나를
팔았습니까, 팔지 않았습니까?
Did you, or did you not sell five
baggies of marijuana to this woman?
팔았어요. 요전 날에요
Yeah, the other day.
단지, 전부 마리화나는 아니었을 뿐이죠
Only, it wasn't all marijuana.
그럼 뭐였죠?
What was it?
몇 봉지는 제가 인터넷에서
구한 눈속임용이었어요
Some of the bags were just some
phony stuff I got off the Internet.
얼만큼이죠?
How many?
꽤 됐어요 / 구체적으로 말씀해 주시죠
A lot. / Be specific.
세 봉지요
Three.
케인 반장이 이 진술을 대가로
Do you swear, under oath,
that Lieutenant Caine
무언가를 약속하지 않았다고
맹세할 수 있나요?
did not promise you something in
exchange for this statement?
물론입니다
No way.
이것 봐요. 그게 제가
돈을 버는 수법이에요
Look, that's how
I make my money.
대부분 다들 눈치 못 채고 넘어가죠
Most of the time,
people don't even notice.
굉장하네
Great.
웨스트 씨?
Ms. West?
좋아요. 경범죄네요
제 범위 밖이로군요
Fine. Misdemeanor.
It's off my radar.
하지만 당신 실험실은 아니에요
But your lab isn't.
이렇게 용의자가 많으면서
쓸 만한 증거가 없던 적은 처음이야
I have never had so many suspects
and so little useful evidence.
이것도 현장에서 가져온 거야?
Did this come from
the crime scene?
음... 네. 그건 침대 옆
테이블에 있었어요
Um... yeah, it was on
a bedside table.
그건...
It's an...
향기를 뿜는 기계예요
aromatic disbursement unit.
뭐라고? / 향기가 디스크에
저장되어 있다가
What? / Fragrances
are stored on a disc,
방으로 퍼지는 거예요
then broadcast into a room.
첨단 공기 청정기 같은 건가?
Like a high-tech air freshener?
네. 바로 그런 거예요
Yeah, exactly.
시간 장치가 있는데
It's on a timer.
왜 그렇게 보세요?
Why do you have that look?
우리가 지금 막 사건을 해결한 건지도 몰라
We may have just broke the case.
좋아. 이 기계를 이제 이해한 것 같아
Okay, I think I've got
this thing figured out.
디스크마다 다섯 종류의 향기가 들어 있어
There are five different
fragrances per disc.
그리고 각 향은 30분마다 방출 되고요
And each aroma is
dispersed for half an hour.
전원의 소나무 향, 봄의 재스민 향
대양의 빗물 향
"Country pine, jasmine
spring, ocean rain,
오렌지 풍의 향, 바다의 산들바람 향
orange spice and sea breeze."
그리고 각 디스크는 2시간 반 동안
향기를 내죠
So, each disc plays
for two and a half hours.
그리고 우리는 몇 시에
기계가 켜졌는지 알고 있지
And we know what time
the machine was turned on.
네. 9시 30분이죠 / 맞아
Yeah, 9:30. / Exactly.
그러니까 우리는 어떤 향이
몇 시에 방출됐는지를 알 수 있지
So, we know which fragrance was
being disbursed at which time.
이 결과를 좋아하게 되실 거예요
향기 디스크를 분석해 달라고 했는데요
You're going to love this.
I had the lab check the disc,
전부 평범한 거였어요
and everything's typical...
마지막 향만 빼고요
except for the last scent.
그건 뭔데?
What is it?
인간 페로몬요
Human pheromones.
풍매성 탄수화물 분자, 최음제
Airborne hydrocarbon
molecules. Aphrodisiac.
전부 누군가를 유혹할 때 나오는 거죠
That's all part of the seduction.
그럼 인간 페로몬이 마지막으로
뿌려진 향이네
Okay, so human pheromones
were the last scent disbursed.
그걸로 시간대를 추정할 수 있죠
Which gives us a time frame.
11시 30분에서 자정 사이야
11:30 to midnight.
다시 셔츠를 살펴 보자
Let's go back to the shirts.
그래요. 토드 매닝 거 말이죠
Yeah. Todd Manning's.
그거랑 그 방에 있던 사람들 것 모두
Along with everyone else in the room.
어때?
How'd we do?
헤더 라킨의 공단 웃옷은
오스만투스 오일이랑
Heather Larkin's satin top was
exposed to osmanthus oil,
시트르산, 그리고 유칼립투스에
노출되었군요
citric acid and eucalyptus.
- 오렌지 풍의 향이네
- 네, 맞아요
- Orange spice.
- Yeah, exactly.
웨인 레이놀즈의 셔츠는
샴페인, 시가 연기
Wayne Reynolds' shirt had
traces of champagne,
그리고 코롱의 성분이 있어요
cigar smoke and cologne.
피해자 것은 어때?
What about our victim?
폴 샌더스의 셔츠는
연기, 땀 그리고
Paul Sanders' shirt was
exposed to smoke, sweat,
오렌지 풍의 향...
orange spice...
엄청난 양의 페로몬에 노출되었네요
and a heavy dose of pheromones.
토드 매닝은?
What about Todd Manning?
1시까지는 시신을 발견 못했잖아
He didn't discover the
body till around 1:00.
토드 매닝 옷은 페로몬으로 시작해요
He was started in pheromones.
우리가 알기론 그게
11시 반에서 자정 사이에
Which we know were being
disbursed into the room
그 방에 퍼진 거잖아
between 11:30 and midnight.
바로 사망 시간 즈음이죠
Which was right around
the time of the death.
토드 매닝은 범행이 일어날 때
그 방에 있었던 거야
Todd Manning was in that
room at the time of the murder.
제가 마이애미 경찰에 연락하죠
I'll call MDPD.
꼬시기 예술가를 꼬셔오라고 해야겠어요
Have them pick up
the pickup artist.
좋아
Great.
내가 여자를 데리고 갔을 때
그런 걸 수도 있잖아요
Hey, could've happened when
I brought that chick up there.
다... 당신들은 증명할 수 없을걸요
You... you can't prove a thing.
- 사실은 할 수 있어요
- 방법은 이렇죠...
- Actually, we can.
- Here's the thing...
그 향 분사기는...
that aroma dispenser...
시간 장치가 있더군요
It was on a timer.
그래서 페로몬이 그 방에 퍼진
We were able to pinpoint
exactly what time the
정확한 시간을 알 수 있었어요
pheromones were
disbursed into the room.
Z-nose라는 기계가 있는데
We have an instrument
called a Z-nose,
당신 셔츠에서 어떤 냄새가
발견되는지 알려줄 거예요
and it will tell us specifically
what odors are found in your shirt.
당신 옷은 11시 반에서 자정 사이에
Your clothes were saturated in
pheromones between the hours
뿌려진 페로몬이 잔뜩 스며 있더군요
of 11:30 and midnight.
검시관이 말한 피해자의
사망 시각과 일치하는 시간이죠
That's when our M.E. tells us
the victim was murdered.
이봐! 저 여자는 내 누나라고
무슨 짓을 한 거야?
Dude! That girl's my sister, man.
What'd you do to her?
해 버렸지
Did her, dude.
한 번 더 하자고 애걸하던걸
She was begging me to do it again.
그냥 내버려 둘 수 없었어
그 여자는 최고였거든
Can't wait.
Chick's a winning horse.
네가 다 망쳤어
그 여자는 내 누나라고
That's messed up, man.
She's my sister.
모든 여자는 누군가의 누나나 여동생이야
Every chick is somebody's sister.
잊어버려
Get over it.
얼음송곳을 가져가진 않았나요?
You didn't bring the ice pick?
샌더스가 가져온 거예요
Sanders brought it.
세미나의 일부였죠
It was part of the seminar.
여자에게 인상 깊을 만한
비싼 물건을 가져오기요
Bring your own high-end
stuff to impress the women.
자기 결혼 선물 중에
하나를 가져온 건가요?
He brought one of
his wedding gifts?
네. 그 녀석은 냉혈한이었어요
Yeah. Dude was cold.
그러니 제가 왜 그랬는지 이해하시겠죠?
Now you know why I did it.
남자라면 자기 여자 형제를
위해서 나설 줄도 알아야 하잖아요
A man's got to stand
up for his sister.
혈육은 혈육이니까요. 안 그래요?
I mean, blood is blood, you know?
그렇죠
Yeah.
다만 폴 샌더스가 거짓말을 한 거예요
Except Paul Sanders lied to you.
뭐라고요?
What?
"자기 판매를 마무리하지 못한" 거죠
He didn't "Close the sale."
무슨 소릴 하시는 거예요?
What are you talking about?
당신 누나는 그 사람이
자길 건들게 두지 않았어요
Your sister didn't
let him touch her.
폴은 체면을 지키려고 거짓말을 했죠
He lied to save face.
누나는 당신을 구하려고 거기 있었던 거예요
She was there to save you...
마법사님
Magic Man.
이런, 맙소사
Oh, God.
아이러니한 건 당신이 뭘 하든지 간에
결국 자신에게로 귀결된다는 거죠
The irony is, where you're going,
you may end up being the target.
케인 반장님?
Lieutenant Caine?
반장님?
Lieutenant?
마리솔
Marisol.
이해가 안 돼요...
절 풀어 줬어요
I... I don't understand...
they released me.
글쎄... 그런 일이 다시
생길 순 없겠죠?
Well... that can't
happen again, can it?
무슨 말씀이신지 알겠어요 / 좋아요
Point taken. / Okay.
반장님, 제가 어떻게 감사드리면 될까요?
Lieutenant, how can
I ever thank you?
그럴 필요 없습니다
That's not necessary.
제가 저녁이라도 대접해 드릴게요
Could I make you dinner?
최소한 그건 할 수 있어요
It's the least that I could do.
아시겠지만...
You know...
아시겠지만, 제 생각엔...
You know, I don't, uh...
그렇게 좋은 생각 같지는 않군요
I don't think that would
be a very good idea.
제 동생이 반장님 밑에서
일하니까요 / 그래요
Because my brother
works for you. / Yeah.
그것도 한 부분이죠. 아시죠?
That's a part of it.
You know?
그냥 저녁 식사일 뿐인데요
It's just dinner.
제가 로파 비에카를 아주 잘 만드는데요
You know, I make a mean ropa vieja.
그래요?
그럼요
You do, huh?
Mm-hmm.
음... 좋아요. 그럼...
Um... Okay. Um...
몇 시가 좋을까요?
What time were you thinking?
8시는 어때요?
Eight o'clock?
8시요
Eight o'clock.
좋아요. 그럼 기대하고 있을게요
Great. I am looking forward to it.
그때 봬요
See you then.
번역수정
이재연(vostoc@nate.com)
한글수정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)